Good evening, sir. How was your day?
晚上好，先生。今天过的怎么样
Being a lawyer stinks, Geoffrey.
当律师真是糟糕透了，Geoffrey
No matter how good a job you do...
不管你的工作做得多么出色
your clients still compare you
to Harry Hamlin.
你的委托人还是拿你
和Harry Hamlin（电影演员）比
Yes. The resemblance is quite striking.
是的，你们相似点确实很多。
Come on, baby. Get on the soul train.
来，宝贝。快来跳 soul train（一种舞蹈）
l love this kind of dancing,
it makes you feel so young.
我很喜欢这类的舞蹈
让你感觉很年轻
Doesn't that goIden oIdie
take you way back?
这首经典名曲
有没有让你感觉回到了过去?
That was Papa's Got a Brand New Bag...
这首是
recorded 25 Iong years ago
by James Brown...
是由James Brown在25年前录制的
the Granddaddy of SouI.
老爷爷的灵魂
We'II be right back
after this message from GeritoI.
广告之后
马上回来
And the Fresh Prince
drives down the court.
新鲜王子带球冲到了前场
He stops, he pops, and it's.... Yes!
瞄准，投篮....进了，太好了
No.
一点也不好
Will, don't play inside.
You might break something.
Will，不要家里面玩
你可能会打坏东西
Or something might break you.
或者什么东西打坏你
l'm sorry. You don't have a hoop outside.
我很抱歉。你们家外面没有篮筐
And Jazz is getting tired of standing
on the second-floor balcony...
Jazz已经厌倦了站在二楼阳台上
holding a pool skimmer.
端着一个破篮筐
Come on, Prince, man.
l know a playground in my neighborhood.
走吧，哥们
我知道我邻居家有个球场
'Course we can only play half-court.
但是我们只能打半场的
They use the other end
to sell stolen appliances.
他们用另外半场
去卖那些偷来的小东西
Dope. Let's go.
碉堡了。走起
Hold on. We don't want you playing there.
等下。我们不希望你们在那里玩
There's a perfectly good basketball court
at the school, where Carlton is practicing.
学校里有一个很完美的篮球场
Carlton就在那边练习
Carlton's on the basketball team?
那货还会打篮球？
How do they do?
他们打的怎么样
They try hard, but to tell you the truth,
they haven't won a game so far.
他们很努力，但是说实话
他们到现在为止还没赢过
Aunt Viv, don't you think
if we went down to watch them practice...
VIv小姨，你不觉得我们
去看他们训练
Carlton would be a little embarrassed?
Carlton会有点小尴尬吗
-Let's go.
-走起
All right.
好吧
Good try!
做的很好
Man, these guys need help.
哥们，这些人需要挽救
Help? They need a telethon.
挽救？他们应该上慈善节目去娱乐大众
He threw that ball to me.
那个球是传给我的
l'm on the other team.
l'm supposed to try and get it.
我是另外一个队的
我本就该努力断球
-You don't have to be rude about it.
-You two, make up right now.
-你没必要抢的那么粗鲁
-你们俩，赶紧和解。
All right, men. Another brilliant warm-up.
好极了 又一次完美的热身
Frankly, l think there's been
way too much emphasis over the years...
坦白说，这些年我已经用很多种
方式去强调
on putting the ball
actually through the hoop.
把球投进篮框
So let's practice some passing.
所以让我们练习下传球吧
-Coach Smiley, may l have a minute?
-Sure.
-Smiley教练，能说句话不
-当然
All right, men, take five.
先这样。小休一下
Headmaster Thorvald, good afternoon.
Thorvard校长，下午好
This is Barry O'Donnell.
He's a distinguished alumnus...
这个是 Barry O'Donnell
他是一名杰出校友
and l'm encouraging him to donate money
for a new gymnasium.
我正在和他讨论为
新的健身房捐钱的事情
Coach. What do you think
the team's prospects are this year?
教练。你认为今年球队的的目标
是什么
For what?
什么目标
For winning.
赢球的目标
Excuse me.
不好意思
What about those two?
You've been holding out on me.
那两个怎么样
你一直瞒着我
Now those are players.
l'd like to meet them.
我很愿意见见
这些球员们
Gentlemen.
先生们
Not you.
不是你们
You two, come on over.
l want you to meet somebody.
你们俩过来一下
我想让你们见个人
Mr. Thorvald,
straight up, about that fire alarm:
实话实说，那个报警铃
l don't know who pulled it.
我也不知道谁拉的
Forget about it.
旧事莫要重提
l'd like you to meet two
of Bel-Air Academy's newest recruits.
为你介绍一下，这是贝莱尔学院
的最新成员
This is Will Smith and.... Your name is....
这是Will Smith，你的名字是？
Jazz, man.
Jazz，哥
Of course, Mr. Jazzman.
哦对，Jazz哥先生
Will, where have you been hiding yourself?
Will，你以前跑哪里去了
What do you mean? During gym class?
什么意思？上体育课的时候？
No. l just wondered, how'd you two men
like to join the school team?
不是。我刚刚在想
你们俩觉得加入校队怎么样
Man, l ain't even in this school.
哥们，我根本不是这个学校的
l'm willing to look past that if you are.
如果你加入的话我愿意接受
Coach, he can't be on the team
if he's not in school here.
教练，如果他不在这个学校上学
是不能进入校队的
Okay. How about you, Will?
Okay。你呢，Will？
l was just trying to find
somewhere to play.
我就是想找个地方打篮球
You join this team,
you can play here anytime you want.
你加入校队
什么时候想打都可以
-No, l don't think so.
-lt'll look good on a college application.
-不，我还得考虑考虑
-这对申请大学有好处
l don't know, Coach.
我还是很犹豫，教练
All right. l'll give you my car.
再退一步。我把车借给你
Okay, this is gonna be fun.
Okay，这会很好玩
The coach asked me to go through
the playbook with you.
教练让我和你讨论下
战术
Your team doesn't need a playbook.
They need a prayer book.
战术什么对这个队不管用吧
你们需要一本祈祷书
Now, pay attention.
现在，注意听讲
This is you...
这是你
and this is me.
这是我
Carlton, you got it wrong already.
lt's more like this.
Carlton，你大错特错了
应该这样画
This is me.
这是我
And this is you.
这是你
Fair enough.
真公平
This is my brain...
这是我的大脑
and this is your brain.
这是你的大脑
This is my handsome face.
这是哥那张帅气到家的脸
And this is your ugly
little Frankenstein face.
这是你那张丑如little Frankenstein（丑陋无比的怪物）的脸
-Give me that chalk.
-Come on, man, beat it.
-把粉笔给我
-来啊，想要就来抢
-Give it.
-Ashley!
-给我
-Ashley！
Here, Ashley,
finally there's an adult in the room.
给我吧，Ashley
这个屋子了总算是有个成熟的人了
Guys, l'm trying to study.
What are you doing?
你们这些家伙，我在努力学习呢
你们干吗呢？
-Keep away from Carlton.
-Over here.
-别让Carlton抢到粉笔
-这！这！这！
Children, please!
小孩们，拜托
What if your parents witnessed
this horseplay?
如果让你们父母目睹了这种恶作剧可不好
-Give me that chalk immediately.
-Keep it away from Carlton!
-快把粉笔传给我！
-别让Carlton抢到！
Keep away from Carlton and Geoffrey.
游戏规则变一下，别让
Carlton和Geoffrey抢到！
You've met your match, Master William.
William少爷，这可是你自找的
Geoffrey, get off me, man.
Geoffrey，快放开我
Geoffrey?
Geoffrey？
May l get you something, sir?
需要我为您做些什么吗，先生？
No, thank you.
不了，谢谢
Will, how many times
do l have to tell you...
Will，我告诉过你多少次了
that this is our living room?
这是咱们的客厅
How'd you like it if l went into your room
and started throwing chalk around?
如果我到你屋里去扔粉笔
你会怎么想
l'd be devastated.
我会和你一起扔
Out.
滚
-Why did you do that?
-What?
-你为这么什么做？
-什么？
You singled Will out.
They were all goofing around.
你把Will赶出去了
他们只是随便玩玩
He was the mastermind. Trust me.
他绝对是主谋。相信我
l just wish you'd be nicer to Will.
我只是希望你对Will好一点
He joined the basketball team
and you haven't said a word about it.
他加入了篮球队
你却只字未提
-Give him some credit.
-All right. l see your point.
-多给他赞扬和信任
-好吧，我懂你意思了
Besides, l think it's a great opportunity
for you two to find some common ground.
此外，我认为这是你们俩找到
共同点的好机会
After all, you were kind of
a star athlete in college.
毕竟你是学校的体育之星
''Kind of a star athlete''?
“体育之星?”
All right. You were a football god.
好吧，你是足球上帝
Okay. Who knows,
it might do him some good.
就这样吧，谁知道呢
可能这样会对他好一点
Nothing like a little organized sport
to straighten a guy out.
没什么有比一项运动
更能让他改邪归正的了
Yes. lt did wonders for Pete Rose.
对，对Pete Rose（棒球运动员）来说是个奇迹
Hilary, l appreciate you coming tonight.
l know you're not a big sports fan.
Hilary，我非常感谢你今天能来
我知道你并不太喜欢运动类的
Mother, please,
it's Will's first game with the team.
妈呀，拜托。
这是Will的第一场比赛
l'm proud of him.
我太为他自豪了
lf l didn't show up to support him,
what kind of cousin would l be?
如果我连着都不支持他，
我算是哪门子表姐呢？
lt'll be three hours well spent.
这将会是三个小时的视觉盛宴
Three hours?
三个小时？
Five, four, three, two, one!
5，4，3，2，1！
l'm going to Disneyland!
我要去迪斯尼乐园了
You did all right!
你今晚太棒了
All right, men, good game on Friday.
棒极了。周五的比赛打得不错
But we can do even better this week.
但是这周我们可以做的更好
-So let's go over some plays.
-Sorry l'm late, Coach!
让我们重温下战术
对不起 教练 我迟到了
Sorry isn't good enough, Cartwell.
Cartwell 光道歉是不够的
-l was under the assumption--我有有原因的
-You made an assumption.你认为你有原因的
Don't make an assumption...让我告诉你原因
because you will be an ass...
因为你是一个傻逼
and the ump will shun you.
连裁判都无视你
Cartwell, after practice,
you give me 10 laps around the school.
Cartwell 训练结束后 你给我绕学校跑十圈
Yes, Coach.
好的 教练
Now let's take a look at this play.
现在 我们一起看下战术
What's up? lt's my squad.
你们好吗 我的篮球队
Sorry l'm late, Coach.
教练 对不起 我迟到了
Don't worry about it, Smith.
没关系 Smith
You just take it easy.
Save that energy for the game.
你只需要放轻松，为比赛节省能量
But l was late, and l have to run 10 laps.
但是我迟到了，却要跑十圈
Twenty laps. Now, shut up.
二十圈  闭嘴
First play. Guard inbounds to the center.
第一种战术 后卫发边线球给中锋
Center moves down court, fakes right,
passes to the forward.
中锋带球过半场 站好位 传球给前锋
What does he do?
他该怎么做
-Passes to Will?
-Bingo.
传给威尔
答对了
Second play. Jump ball.
Ball is tipped to the center.
第二中战术 跳球
把球拨给中锋
Center shuttles to the guard,
back to the center...
中锋传给后卫，然后后卫再回传给中锋
who hits to the forward
and over to baseline.
在传给前锋 在给到45°底线
-What does he do?
-Passes to Will.
下一步他该怎么做
传给威尔
Yes!
答对了
Okay. Number three.
好了，第三种
Forward inbounds from here...
前锋从这边发球
bounce pass to the guard,
who zips it back to the forward...
先传给后卫 再回传给在篮地下的前锋
under the net. What does he do?
他该怎么做
lf he's clear, he goes for the lay-up.
Otherwise, back to the guard.
如果无人防守 他直接上篮
否则回传给后卫
Okay, Banks, not paying attention?
Ten laps.
Banks 心不在焉 罚绕学校跑十圈
Not paying attention?
Look at Will. He's asleep.
心不在焉？ 看看威尔 他睡着了
Mind your own business, Banks.
That's 20 laps.
Banks 管好你自己吧 罚跑20圈
NBA superstar Isaiah Thomas
is used to having things his own way.
NBA超级巨星伊萨亚托马斯以前一直非常厉害
But not today.
但今天不行
How do you do it, Prince?
王子 你怎么做到的
Easy, Isaiah
Isaiah 小意思
Air Fresh gym shoes. Just pass it to WiII.
Air Fresh篮球鞋 把球传给威尔
Hi, pumpkin. Hi, love.
嗨 小南瓜 嗨 亲爱的
-Hi.
-ls Will home yet?
-Hi
-Will回家了吗
He's outside playing basketball
with Carlton.
他在外面和Carlton打篮球呢
Come on, Will. Now let me down.
拜托，Will，现在放我下来吧
Will, would you come in here
a minute, please?
Will，你能过来下不
What's going on?
啥情况
l've been thinking about what you said
about us finding some common ground.
关于你说的共同点这件事，
我已经认真的想过了
-Good.
-The firm has season tickets...
-太好了
公司有湖人队的季票
for the Laker game, so l put in for them.
l thought we could go.
我想我们可以一起去看
Philip, what a great idea. He'll love it.
Philp，这是个多么的好的主意啊。他会爱死的
Thank you.
谢谢
Uncle Phil, thanks for putting
the hoop up on the garage.
Phill叔叔，谢谢你在车库装了个篮筐
lt's really helping my lay-ups, Dad.
Come on out, l'll show you.
这对我的上篮很有帮助
出来 我给你秀一个
Sounds great, Carlton,
but in a minute, okay?
听起来很不错，Carlton
但是稍等下哈？
-You wanted to talk to me?
-l have two tickets to the Lakers game.
-你想和我说话？
-我有两张湖人队的票
-How'd you like to come?
-Word, l'm with that.
-想不想来？
好啊，我去
Give the Laker girls an opportunity
to check out a future Laker.
给湖人啦啦队一个机会检验下未来的湖人球员
Yeah, right.
对啊
Son, you want to show me those lay-ups?
儿子，你想让我看看上篮？
Maybe a little bit later.
Actually, l've got some studying to do.
还是一会再说吧
说实话我现在必须得去写作业了
-After dinner?
-Okay.
-饭后?
-没问题
-Uncle Phil, want to shoot a few hoops?
-Sure.
-Phil，想投个篮不？
-当然
Did l tell you how my high-school team
won the state championship?
我告诉过你在高中
校队赢得洲冠军了吗？
l made the final basket right at the buzzer.
是我投进的绝杀
That's decent.
太牛逼了
-Hi, Carlton.
-Hi, Hilary.
-Hilary, can l ask you something?
-Sure.
-Hilary，我能问你点事不？
-当然
How was l in the basketball game
last Friday?
我上周五的比赛打的
怎么样
You were great. You didn't make
any baskets or anything...
我打的很好。虽然你没怎么进球
but you looked cute in your uniform.
但是你穿球衣的样子看起来很可爱
l think it's great
how you don't get it too sweaty.
我认为你很努力了 虽然你没出什么汗
l guess it's 'cause you don't run too fast.
Smart move.
我猜是因为你跑不快
太机智了
Did Dad mention me during the game?
爸爸在比赛的时候有提到我吗？
He did turn around
to the guy behind him once and say:
有次他转过身
对后面的人喊了句
''Shut up.
That's my son you're talking about.''
“闭嘴”
“你们现在说的那个是我儿子”
lt's Will, isn't it?
是因为Will，是吧？
No. lt's not.
不。不是的
Talk to me.
和我说说
Look, it's ridiculous
to compare yourself to Will.
听着，把你自己和Will去比
太荒唐了
You're captain of the debate team,
a straight ''A'' student...
你是辩论队的队长
三好学生
you're leader of the glee club.
So what if Will's good at basketball?
你是歌队的领唱
那么威尔擅长打篮球又能怎么样呢
Thanks, Hilary. That means a lot to me.
谢谢，Hilary。这对我来说很重要
Besides, if that basket
were two feet lower...
顺便说一句
如果篮筐矮两头
you'd be just as good as he is.
你会打的和他一样好
Geoffrey, l'm surprised
you decided to come.
Geoffrey，我很惊讶的看到
你决定一起来
You're not a basketball fan.
你一直不喜欢篮球的
True, madam, but l have found
that any game can be made interesting...
确实，夫人。
但是我发现如果赌球的话
if you put a little money on it.
你对任何运动都会感兴趣了
-You bet on this game?
-$50 says Bel-Air wins it.
-这场比赛你下注了？
-50刀赌Bel-Air赢
Who'd take that bet?
和谁赌的？
You rang, beautiful?
美女 你在召唤我吗
Jazz, you bet against Will?
Jazz，你不 赌Will赢？
Yeah. He screws up, l'm loaded.
是啊 他输球了 我就发了
Students, parents, aIumni,
Iet me introduce our beIoved coach...
学生们，家长们，校友们
先让我们介绍一下教练
Herb SmiIey.
Herb SmiIey
Thank you.
谢谢
I see a Iot of new faces out here tonight...
今天晚上看到了很多新面孔...
那些我们输球的时候不在的.
PeopIe who did not support this team
in its darkest hour.
那些在球队最灰暗的时候
不支持球队的人.
All I can say is, I don't blame you one bit.
我能说的就是，我一点也不怪你们
HaIf the time, I didn't want to be there.
每次到半场的时候我都呆不下去了
And quite frankIy,
I usuaIIy ducked out a IittIe earIy.
坦白的说, 我经常提前一点点偷偷的退场
But that's aII gonna change tonight
because of our new superstar...
但是今晚一切都将改变
因为我们拥有了一颗超新星
WiII Smith.
威尔史密斯
With seven seconds remaining,
BeI-Air is down by two points...
只剩下7秒了
BeI-Air还落后两分
and caIIs a time out.
叫了一个暂停
Our only hope for winning this game
is by shooting a three-pointer.
我们唯一赢的希望就是
投进那个三分
So here's the plan.
Cartwell, you inbound to Hunt.
所以计划是这样的
-Hunt, what do you do?
-Shoot for the three-pointer?
-Hunt， 你要做的是什么？
-试投三分？
Very funny.
That'll be 10 laps, chowderhead.
逗逼
跑十圈 傻逼
-What's the right answer?
-Pass it to Will.
-正确答案是什么？
-传给Will
All right. Now, let's do it.
齐活了。现在，上场吧
One, two, three, Bel-Air!
1，2，3. Bel-Air！
Oh, my God.
我滴神啊
Yes!
Thirty, forty, fifty!
30，40，50！
-There.
-Thanks, man.
-就这样了
-谢谢，哥们
Nice doing business with you.
和你做生意真好
Mr. Jazz,
the World Snooker Championship...
Jazz先生，
斯诺克冠军赛
is on the sports station in a few moments.
马上就要开始了
Would you care to place a wager?
想不想赌一发？
-l don't know anything about snooker.
-Don't worry.
-我对斯诺克什么都不知道啊
-别担心
l'll tell you everything you need to know.
你想知道的，我都能告诉你
l'm going to shoot some hoops.
lf you'd like to practice...
我要去练下投篮
你要是想练习
some new and more spectacular ways
to lose a game, please join me.
一些更新奇更壮观输球大法
那就一起来吧
-Put that down.
-Put what down?
-把那个放下
-把什么放下？
-My basketball.
-Your basketball?
-我的篮球
-你的篮球？
Excuse me, your name is Spalding?
不好意思。你的名字是斯伯丁（品牌名称）？
Dad gave it to me for my birthday
three years ago.
那是三年前爸爸给我的生日礼物
lt's my ball. Give it.
我的球，还给我
ln a bad mood? You should be
the happiest guy in the world.
生什么气呢？你应该是现在世界上
最幸福的人了
Yeah? Why?
耶？为什么？
'Cause you got out
of that locker room alive.
因为你是活着走出更衣室的
Man, Coach Smiley was upset.
哥们，Smiley教练伤心坏了
Boy, you're lucky
that was just a starter's pistol.
你真心运气不错
那只是一只发令枪
l was trying to win the game.
我是努力去赢球的
No, you were trying to be the hero.
没有。你只是想成为英雄
Somebody else can be the hero
besides you all the time.
你身边的任何一个
随时都有机会成为英雄
Let's get something straight.
有话直说了
l been here for two months.
l been getting yelled at at home...
我到这两个月了
在家里被骂
screamed at at school,
l been sent to detention, grounded...
学校里被骂
被留校和禁足
threatened with expulsion
on almost a daily basis.
被威胁退学
已经成为家常便饭了
l finally do something l get credit for,
and you can't take it.
我终于能做一件受表扬的事情了
你却受不了了
Man, l got news for you.
我想对你说的就是
l ain't about to sell myself short
just to make you feel better. Grow up!
我不会为了让你觉得开心一点
而贬低自己   成熟点吧
You should grow up,
hogging the ball every chance you get!
是你应该长大点
一旦拿到球从不传球
-l wasn't hogging nothing.
-You were!
-我才没粘球呢
-你有！
Okay, you two.
你们俩够了
What's this all about?
特么的在说什么呢
Carlton doesn't want me
to use his basketball...
Carlton不想我用他的篮球
'cause he's afraid
l might get it in the basket.
估计是因为怕我把篮球
投进了
Will you two start acting your age?
你们能做点你们这个年纪该做的事吗
What l saw on that basketball court
tonight was a disgrace.
我今天晚上在球场上看到的
没有丢人，只有更丢人
lf l'd made that last shot,
l'd be the hero right now.
如果我投进了绝杀
我现在就是英雄了
Carlton, the fact that you missed the shot
wasn't a disgrace.
Carlton，事实上你投丢了
没有什么丢人的
You stole the ball
from a member of your own team.
丢人的是你和自己的
队友去抢球
Yeah, and if you'd passed it to me,
we would've won.
是，如果传给我了
我们已经赢了
You would?
你会？
Of course, l can make that shot
with my eyes closed...
必须的，那个球我闭着眼睛都能投进
-and one hand tied behind my back.
-Was that gonna be your next trick?
-甚至只用单手
-这会演变成你又一个谎话吗？
'Cause you were like
a one-man circus out there.
因为你在那儿看起来像是
一人马戏团里
Uncle Phil, the coach told the team
to pass the ball to me.
Phil叔叔，是教练告诉全队
把球传给我的
Did he tell you to woof at the crowd...
他还告诉你学鸡叫
kiss the cheerleader between plays,
and shoot the ball backwards?
比赛的时候去亲啦啦队
还告诉你要去背身投篮？
No, l came up with all that fly stuff myself.
没有，我总是要有一些创意的
That wasn't fly, Will.
威尔 这么做没用的
A real star plays with the team.
一个真正的巨星应该注重团队合作
Maybe you should think about that.
你应该好好去想想
Carlton, can l ask you something?
Carlton，能问你件事吗
Sure.
可以
When you stole the ball from Will
and tried to make that Hail Mary shot...
当你把球从Will手里偷走
想去投？？？？
what were you thinking about?
你他妈脑子里想的什么啊
-l don't know.
-Really?
-我不知道
-真的？
l guess l was just thinking
of the first game Will won...
我想我是在想Will赢了
第一场比赛
and how you ran out on the court
and you were so proud of him.
你跑进了场地
你为他有多自豪
l guess l thought it would be cool
if it happened to me.
我想那要是发生在我身上
该有多好
Carlton, you don't have to be a hero.
Carlton，你没必要成为那个英雄
l'm proud that you're out there
giving it all you got.
只要你在场上拼尽全力
我就会为你自豪
You started coming to games
when Will joined the team.
Will进了校队之后你才去
看比赛的
-l wanted to support him.
-You wouldn't come when it was just me.
-我想支持他
-但是只有我的时候你没有支持
l'd like to come to everything you do.
我很愿意为你去做任何事
l always come to your tennis games,
to your debate matches...
你的每次网球比赛辩论会
your glee club concerts.
你的翻唱团演唱会
Frankly, keeping up
with your extracurricular activities...
和你去那些课外班 坦白说
is a 24-hour-a-day job.
就是个24小时的活
Did l mention
l was elected editor of the yearbook?
我说过我被选中成为年刊的编辑了吗？
l didn't mean to slight you.
我没有想轻视你
But l can't slight Will, either.
但是我也不能轻视Will
His mother is 3,000 miles away.
他的妈妈在3000英里之外地方
He needs a cheering section
as much as you do.
他也需要和你一样多的支持
Maybe more.
甚至更多
-l'm gonna head up. Good night, son.
-Good night, Dad.
-我明天还得早起。晚安，儿子
-晚安，爸爸
Will.
威尔
Yeah?
什么事
Here.
给你